

AGNES MUTUA

HR GENERALIST

Experience: 5 years | Available: Immediately | Location: Nairobi

magneskasyoka@gmail.com | +254710931912

ABOUT ME



Passionate Human Resource Generalist with over 5 years of experience in recruitment and selection, employee training, employee relations, performance management, policies development, records management, Hr administration, occupational health and safety, HR Information systems and legal compliance. A holder of a Higher Diploma in Human Resource Management, A Diploma in personnel management and currently pursuing Bsc. Human Resource Management at Moi University. Full Member of the Institute of Human Resource Management

WORK EXPERIENCE



TRANSAFRICA PAPER MILLS LIMITED

Management level | HR ASSISTANT NAIROBI , Kenya 2016-04-01 | 2018-04-01

- . conducting performance appraisals
- Increasing engagement of the employees, through meetings and regular training sessions
- Enhance good working environment by creating harmonious relations
- Identifying training needs of staff across all departments and taking the necessary steps and actions to ensure that the training is effectively implemented
- Ensuring that disciplinary steps are taken at all levels in the organization when and where the need arises
- Ensuring that HR costs are managed within budget
- Continuously reviewing and maintaining optimum level of staffing including the required competence matrix for all departments and positions
- Accountable for Mill wide housekeeping
- Ensure the company complies with legal regulations and statutory laws through renewal of legal permits and licenses
- Prepare HR monthly reports and circulate to the management
- Maintaining organization staff by establishing a recruiting, testing, and interviewing program, advising managers on candidate selection; conducting and analyzing exit interviews, recommending changes
- Ensure a succession planning plan is in place for all departments
- Provide guidance, direction and advice to management on human resource related matters

- Ensure that employee records are updated, maintained and confidential at all times
- Chair the occupational health and safety committee and its meetings. Deliberate and ensure full compliance with the health and safety act.
- Leave management

Workman compensation

H YOUNG CONSTRUCTION COMPANY EA LTD

Mid level | ASSISTANT HR MANAGER
NAIROBI, Kenya
2018-04-01 | Currently working here

Checking background information for prospective employees
Staff on boarding
Conducting interviews
Junior staff medical reimbursements
Liaising with payroll department to ensure that the correct employee information is provided, advising on employee exits, new employees and any salary reviews
Maintaining employees records
Facilitates payment of final dues to employees separating with the company
Preparing appointment letters for new employees

EDUCATION



EAST AFRICA SCHOOL OF MANAGEMENT

Diploma | DIPLOMA IN PERSONNEL MANAGEMENT

BEAM INTERNATIONAL TRAINING CENTRE

Diploma | HIGHER DIPLOMA IN HUMAN RESOURCE MANAGEMENT

Preparing certificates of service for the employees leaving the company

Providing HR support and advice to the site administrators

□ Representing the company in court cases – employment matters

JOB SKILLS

316

Employee Relations

Performance management

Problem solving

HR information systems

Multitasking

LANGUAGE SKILLS



English

Swahili

ASSOCIATIONS

IHRM: ASSOCIATE MEMBER

IHRM: MEMBER

